

Contact

- Mobile: +918697148813
- E-mail: rayprateek95@gmail.com
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ prateek-ray
- Address: Baduria, West Bengal - 743401

Skills

Copywriting **Branding Content Writing** SEO, SEM, SMM **Digital Marketing** MS Office **Google Analytics Data Analytics** Power BI Python SQL C, C++ JavaScript, HTML AI/ML **Project Management CRM** Communication Creativity Problem-solving Strategic thinking Creative thinking Adaptability

Hobbies & Interests

Film, Music Modeling Performing Art Poetry and Literature Social Activism Organized and analytical marketing professional with more than 2 years of experience in the field of digital marketing strategies and strong communication and computer skills. Interested in using advanced SEO, Google Analytics Facebook Ads, data mining and Al tools to benefit the organization's clients and raise brand awareness. Offers top skills in planning and project management. Detail-oriented team player with strong organizational skills. Ability to handle multiple projects simultaneously with a high degree of accuracy. Willingness to take on added responsibilities to meet team goals.

Work History

Feb. 2022 -Oct. 2023

Digital Marketing Executive

AdGlobal360 India Pvt. Ltd., Gurgaon

- Led methodology development to outline basic process parameters for operations
- Delivered advertising copy for online content, adhering to employers' overarching brand identity and personality
- Developed short and long-term media outreach strategies in collaboration with cross-functional teams
- Improved search result rankings with a targeted SEO strategy
- Supported branding, digital marketing messaging and advertising campaigns by engaging with followers on various social media platforms
- Developed innovative marketing campaigns to drive substantial sales.

Nov. 2021 -Jan. 2022

Academic Content Researcher

Novelish, Kolkata

- Provided writing support in a fast-paced environment for a variety of public-facing materials
- Utilized exceptional writing, editing, and proofreading skills to produce engaging and error-free content
- Completed thorough research into assigned topics
- Completed writing assignments to set standards regarding order, clarity, conciseness, style and terminology
- Wrote blog and social media posts about assigned topics, implementing SEO to encourage engagement and traffic
- Researched and wrote articles for scholarly work and trade publications.

Aug. 2021 -Oct. 2021

Technical Support Associate

Maviq Software Pvt. Ltd., Kolkata

- Helped customers set up new systems, applications and software
- Provided clear and concise step-by-step technical support to guide clients
- Asked customers targeted questions throughout troubleshooting to determine smart solutions
- Responded to customer emails, calls and live chat regarding technical malfunctions and issues to fix remotely
- Built rapport with customers through courteous and professional communications.

Education

2018 B.Tech. in Electrical Engineering

Dr B C Roy Engineering College (WBUT) - Durgapur, WB

- Graduated with DGPA @ 7.29
- Dissertation in GSM-based Home Security System
- Coursework in Mitsubishi Electric FA Products
- Member of Cultural Society, IEEE Society.